Jacob Hocker

Houston, Texas 77084 | 713-292-6730 | jacobdouglas06@gmail.com Github | Medium Blog | Linked In | Portfolio

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Experience using frontend and backend technologies such as Ruby on Rails, Node, JavaScript, and React. I bring 6 years of working as a Calibration Technician with strong skills in customer service, meeting deadlines, and building relationships. I have a love for learning and constantly challenge myself to master something new. As a developer, I'm excited to be in a collaborative environment and use my creativity and problem-solving skills to help a company create quality products.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Sass (SCSS), Mobile First Responsive Design, SQL, PostgreSQL, Ruby on Rails, GitHub, Heroku, Node, Restful APIs, Object-Oriented Programming, JSON, jQuery, Google, Jest, Agile Development, Swiperis, Emailis

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Entertainment Center - Github | Live Demo

A large database of movies, actors, genres, and directors with an interactive user experience.

- Implemented with a React/SCSS front-end and a Ruby on Rails back-end.
- Utilizes the use of the massive The Movie Database API
- Tailored with the ability to create a simple and clean user experience.
- Ongoing live service application with new feature coming.

OverStat Lab - Github | Demo

Application for Overwatch that includes a search for player statistics, hero/map/O.W.L info database, and a social feature to find other players to play with.

- Created with React/SCSS mobile first responsive design front-end.
- Supplemented with a Ruby on Rails back-end.
- Utilizes a third-party API that runs through the back-end using HTTParty and dotenv gems.
- Supplied an exhaustive back-end API for the heroes and all of the information known about them.
- Provided easy CRUD capabilities.

EXPERIENCE

Hocker, Inc. Houston, Texas Calibration Technician | Website Lead 11/2016 - Present

- Oversee product management and price control on the company website.
- Conduct hardware troubleshooting and software debugging.
- Deliver on deadlines set by customers and manufacturers.

Customer Engineering Services (CES)

Houston, Texas

Technician | Trainer

04/2015 - 11/2016

- Trained 75+ employees on the use and maintenance of photo lab equipment and software.
- Provided on the spot debugging of software issues and hardware complications.
- Presented issues found with software with development teams to assist in rectifying errors.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Houston, Texas Full Stack Software Engineering Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program 05/2021 - 03/2022

Lonestar Community College

Houston, Texas 08/2012 - 04/2014 Coursework completed towards a Bachelors Degree in Audio Engineering